photoshoptrainingchannel.com 2018-12-26

# Privacy Policy

**Updated:** May 24, 2018

**We have created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm and continuing commitment to the privacy of personal information provided by those visiting and interacting with this website. The Photoshop Training Channel hold’s the privacy of your personal information in the highest regard. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for this website.**

### Who We Are

We recognize the importance of protecting your privacy and our policy is designed to assist you in understanding how we collect, use and safeguard the personal information you provide to us and to assist you in making informed decisions when using our site. This policy will be continuously assessed against new technologies, business practices, and our customers’ needs.

The Photoshop Training Channel (PTC) is operated by Jesus Ramirez Media. PTC understands the importance of protecting your personal information and undertakes to adhere to this privacy policy at all times to ensure your personal information is effectively safeguarded. Our website address is: http://jr9982.wpengine.com.

### What Information Do We Collect?

PTC undertakes to collect your personal information only where it is necessary for the purposes of marketing our products and where requested distributing newsletters and responding to sales and technical queries.

In most circumstances, this information will be limited to your contact details, including but not limited to your name, address, e-mail address, company, company ABN, company address, your job title and phone numbers. Where orders are made online using credit card details, all information is securely transmitted in an encrypted format to PTC.

When you visit this website you may provide us with these types of Personal Information You Choose to Provide

  1. **Registration Information**  
When you register for any of our products, services or newsletters you will provide us information about yourself.
  2. **Email Information**  
If you choose to correspond with us through email, we may retain the content of your email messages together with your email address and our responses.
  3. **Web Site Use Information**  
Similar to other commercial Web sites, our Web site utilizes a standard technology called “cookies” and web server log files to collect information about how our Web site is used. Information gathered through cookies and Web server logs may include the date and time of visits, the pages viewed, time spent at our Web site, and the Web sites visited just before and just after our Web site.

PTC collects personal information when you complete one of the following actions:

  * Order products from our online store.
  * Lodge a technical support query regarding PTC’s products or services.
  * Participate in PTC’s promotional activities or surveys.
  * Where you forward information to us in an email or as a hard copy document.
  * Other circumstances where collecting personal information is reasonable and permitted by the Laws of the State of California, USA.

### How Do We Use the Information That You Provide to Us?

PTC may use your personal information for any of the following purposes:

  * Marketing PTC products.
  * Fulfilling orders for PTC products.
  * Updating PTC products.
  * Responding to inquiries about PTC products; and
  * Fulfill all legal requirements of PTC with respect to your personal information.

Personally identifiable information or business information will not be shared with parties except as required by law.

You may notify us at any time if you do not wish to receive these offers by emailing us at the link provided in the newsletter.

### Email Addresses

We respect your privacy. Any information we collect from you, including your email address, will simply be used to send you the information you have requested.

We will not give or sell your personal information. If you give us your email and permission to send more information, you may opt out of receiving any additional email messages at any time, by unsubscribing from our email list.

You may also be asked for email addresses by partners and resources listed on this site after you click on links from this website. Although we strive to link only to reputable organizations, we cannot control their use of your personal data, so be sure you understand the privacy policy of any site and trust them before providing any personal information.

### Choice/Opt-In/Opt-Out

This site allows visitors to unsubscribe so that they will not receive future messages. After unsubscribing we will discontinue sending the particular messages as soon as technically feasible.

### Collection of Personal Information

When visiting The Photoshop Training Channel, the IP address used to access the site will be logged along with the dates and times of access. This information is purely used to analyze trends, administer the site, track users movement and gather broad demographic information for internal use. Most importantly, any recorded IP addresses are not linked to to personally identifiable information.

### Do We Share Your Data?

We do not share, sell, lend or lease any of the information that uniquely identifies a subscriber (such as email addresses or personal details) with anyone except to the extent it is necessary to process transactions or provide services that you have requested.

We may contract with third parties to supply products and services to you on Our behalf. These may include payment processing, delivery of goods, search engine facilities, advertising, and marketing.

In some cases, the third parties may require access to some or all of your data. Where any of your data is required for such a purpose, We will take all reasonable steps to ensure that your data will be handled safely, securely, and in accordance with your rights, Our obligations, and the obligations of the third party under the law. We currently contract with:

Stripe, Paypal, Google, Facebook, and MailChimp

### Links to Third Party Websites

We have included links on this site for your use and reference. We are not responsible for the privacy policies on these websites. You should be aware that the privacy policies of these sites may differ from our own.

### Cookies

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to save your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

We also use cookies to help us show ads and to make recommendations for our products to people who may be interested in Facebook. We also use cookies to help measure the performance of ad campaigns on Facebook Ads. For more details, please read the [Facebook Privacy Policy](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy).

### Log Files

We use IP addresses to analyse trends, administer the site, track user’s movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information. Additionally, for systems administration, detecting usage patterns and troubleshooting purposes, our web servers automatically log standard access information including browser type, access times/open mail, URL requested, and referral URL.

This information is not shared with third parties and is used only within this Company on a need-to-know basis. Any individually identifiable information related to this data will never be used in any way different to that stated above without your explicit permission.

### Third Party Advertisements

We also use third party advertisements on PTC to support our site. Some of these advertisers may use technology such as cookies when they advertise on our site.

Cookies will also send these advertisers (such as Google through the [Google AdSense](https://www.google.com/adsense "Google Adsense") program) information including your IP address, your ISP, the browser you used to visit our site, and in some cases, whether you have Flash installed.

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: <https://automattic.com/privacy/>. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

### Media

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

### Embedded Content From Other Websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

### What We Date We Collect in Our Online Store

While you visit our site, we’ll track:

  * Products you’ve viewed: we’ll use this to, for example, show you products you’ve recently viewed
  * Location, IP address and browser type: we’ll use this for purposes like estimating taxes and shipping
  * Shipping address: we’ll ask you to enter this so we can, for instance, estimate shipping before you place an order, and send you the order!
  * We’ll also use cookies to keep track of cart contents while you’re browsing our site.

When you purchase from us, we’ll ask you to provide information including your name, billing address, shipping address, email address, phone number, credit card/payment details and optional account information like username and password. We’ll use this information for purposes, such as, to:

  * Send you information about your account and order.
  * Respond to your requests, including refunds and complaints.
  * Process payments and prevent fraud.
  * Set up your account for our store.
  * Comply with any legal obligations we have, such as calculating taxes.
  * Improve our store offerings.
  * Send you marketing messages, if you choose to receive them.

If you create an account, we will store your name, address, email and phone number, which will be used to populate the checkout for future orders.

We generally store information about you for as long as we need the information for the purposes for which we collect and use it, and we are not legally required to continue to keep it. For example, we will store order information for 4 years for tax and accounting purposes. This includes your name, email address and billing and shipping addresses.

We will also store comments or reviews, if you choose to leave them.

**Who on our team has access**

Members of our team have access to the information you provide us. For example, both Administrators and Shop Managers can access:

  * Order information like what was purchased, when it was purchased and where it should be sent, and
  * Customer information like your name, email address, and billing and shipping information.
  * Our team members have access to this information to help fulfill orders, process refunds and support you.

### Payments

We accept payments through PayPal and Strip. When processing payments, some of your data will be passed to PayPal or Stripe, including information required to process or support the payment, such as the purchase total and billing information.

Please see the [PayPal Privacy Policy](https://www.paypal.com/us/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full) and the [Stripe Privacy Policy](https://stripe.com/gb/privacy) for more details.

### What About Legally Compelled Disclosure of Information?

We may disclose information when legally compelled to do so, in other words, when we, in good faith, believe that the law requires it or for the protection of our legal rights. We may also disclose account information when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be violating our Terms of Service or to protect the safety of our users and the Public.

### A Special Note About Children

Children are not eligible to use our services unsupervised and we ask that children (under the age of 14) do not submit any personal information to us. If you are a minor, you can use this service only in conjunction with permission and guidance from your parents or guardians.

### Your Consent

By using our Website you consent to our collection and use of your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy. We reserve the right to amend this privacy policy at any time with or without notice.

### Our Commitment To Data Security:

Please note that your information will be stored and processed on our computers in the United States. The laws on holding personal data in the United States may be less stringent than the laws of your Country of residence or citizenship. To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

### Acquisition or Changes in Ownership

In the event that the website (or a substantial portion of its assets) is acquired, your information would be considered part of those assets and may be part of those assets that are transferred.

### Policy Modifications

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. If/when changes are made to this privacy policy, we will email users who have given us permission to do so. We will post any changes here, so be sure to check back periodically. However, please be assured that if the Privacy Policy changes in the future, we will not use the personal information you have submitted to us under this Privacy Policy in a manner that is materially inconsistent with this Privacy Policy, without your prior consent.

### Copyright

Under no circumstance can any content on this website be copied or reproduced in any way. This includes any of the free Photoshop training videos that are hosted on this domain. If any person or company does use the owner of this websites name, video, or blog content without getting written consent from the owner then legal action may be undertaken against the offending parties.

### Privacy Office Contact Details

Should you have any queries in relation to the above or require further information regarding PTC’s collection, use and storage of your personal information please do not hesitate to contact our Privacy Officer at: privacy@photoshoptrainingchannel.com
